Hello everyone and welcome to
English Pond, my name is Marco.
My name is Katherine
and today we're talking
about a kind of education
that is quite unique
actually, a little bit different from the
kind of education that most people get.
That's right, so we normally go to school
to learn, but on this occasion we're going
to talk about a different
way of obtaining your
education, we're talking
about homeschooling someone.
Let's check this word out in
today's vocabulary preview.
All right, so the word
is homeschool to
homeschool someone, it's a verb, and
what does it mean if you're homeschooled?
Well you think about the word school, home
means that you study at home, but you don't
go to school every
day, instead you have a
parent or maybe a friend of a parent who
comes to your house to teach you every day.
So it's basically like
having a tutor for, but
not to help you with
school, but to actually
teach you everything
that you learn at school.
That's right, and some
people are homeschooled
with their siblings, so brothers and
sisters, other people are homeschooled alone.
We'll talk about some
of these things in a
moment, but let's take
a listen to our dialogue.
I think we should homeschool our
children when we decide to have kids.
What?
Why?
Well our public schools
here are not very good,
and the private schools
are just too expensive.
I have been reading up on some homeschooling,
and it has a lot of advantages.
Like what?
I think that by doing
something like that, we
would be isolating our
children from social interaction.
Well first of all, I would be
able to teach them everything
they learned in school in a
more relaxed and fun way.
I also think that having
one-on-one class is
much better since you can focus more
on his or her strengths or weaknesses.
I think neither your parents or
mine would agree to such an idea.
I'll bring it up over Sunday brunch.
Good luck with that.
All right, we're back
so now let's take a look
at some of that language
on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So as we mentioned
in the introduction to
today's podcast, homeschooling is one
of many different educational options.
The most common ones are in the beginning
of the dialogue, public and private school.
Right, so in most places
you will have public
schools where basically the
education is paid for by the government.
Yeah, that's right, so public schools are
schools that are available to all students.
You don't have to pay to attend them.
These are, this is of course in America,
and Britain, the system is a bit different.
But in America, you have the
public schools, which most kids go to.
Of course, if your parents
don't want you to study in public
school, there's another option
that's called private school.
That's right, so a
private school as the
name says, it's not
really private, but what
happens is that it's not
available free for everyone.
You have to actually
pay to go to the school.
That's right, the school
has a tuition, kind
of like a private
college or university.
So you have to pay every
semester or every year.
And usually these schools
also have application standards.
So they interview you,
they interview your parents.
So there's a lot of different things
you have to do to attend these schools.
That's right.
So they're a bit more exclusive.
So these are basically some three options.
You have homeschooling
public schools, private schools.
And while the two parents
are kind of discussing
the options of why it would be maybe not
a good idea to homeschool one of the kids.
And she says that it would be isolating
our children from social interaction.
All right.
So let's take a look at the
word to isolate the subverb.
And I like to think
of island isolate kind
of similar in a way basically to
isolate from is to keep away from.
So if your student
or your child is being
homeschooled, he or she might
be isolated from other students.
They're not near or with other students.
That's right.
So to isolate means to keep
away from or to keep separately.
So like you said,
maybe if you're on an
island, you are isolated
from the rest of the world.
If I live in the country far away from the
city, I feel isolated from other people.
So she's saying that the kid might
be isolated from social interaction.
All right.
Now social interaction.
This is a two word phrase.
We usually take it as a phrase.
This basically means talking to or
playing with other people, other kids.
Right.
So I guess in this case, it's it's
personal or physical social interaction.
As nowadays, you have social
interaction via the internet.
That's right.
But in the case of a
student going to school, it
would be of course
playing on the playgrounds,
attending class, but social interaction
means talking to or being with other people.
That's right.
Well, and the other parent argued
that there are many advantages.
And specifically he said that having a
one on one class is better for the kids.
All right.
So this word one on one.
It refers to one teacher, one
student, one parent, one child.
It means when you're talking to
someone and there's no one else around.
All right.
So usually tutors teach you one on one.
You sit at a table and
your tutor helps you study.
But in the case of homeschooling,
the student learns one on one.
So learns directly from the teacher.
Right.
And that's different
from public schools
obviously because you have one
teacher from maybe 30 students.
That's right.
So that's not one on one.
That's one on many.
Right.
Exactly.
And one is also a word you can
use when you talk about meetings.
So you could say, hey, Marko, can
we have a one on one meeting later?
I'd like to talk to you alone.
So that means I'm not going
to talk to you with other people.
All right.
Okay.
It's like a private meeting.
Yeah.
Very good.
So let's take a listen
to the dialogue again.
And then we're going to come back and we're
going to take a look at some key phrases.
I think we should homeschool our
children when we decide to have kids.
What?
Why?
Well, our public schools
here are not very good
and private schools
are just too expensive.
I've been reading up on some homeschooling
and it has a lot of advantages.
Like what?
I think that by doing
something like that, we would
be isolating our children
from social interaction.
Well, first of all, I
would be able to teach
them everything they learned in
school in a more relaxed and fun way.
I also think that having
one on one class is
much better since you can focus more
on his or her strengths or weaknesses.
I think neither your parents or
mine would agree to such an idea.
I'll bring it up over Sunday, brooch.
Good luck with that.
Alright, we've picked out
four key phrases for you today.
Let's take a look at
those on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
So the first phrase today in fluency
builder is the phrase to read up on.
So the sentence was,
I've been reading up on
homeschooling and it
has a lot of advantages.
Right.
So basically, if you say
you have been reading
up on a subject or a
topic or something,
it means that you've been reading about
it, you've kind of been informing yourself.
You're doing research about a topic.
So in this case, one parent is
researching the homeschooling option.
So here she is reading
maybe articles in a
magazine or books or
looking on the internet.
But you don't actually just
have to read up on education.
You can read up on anything.
Exactly.
So you can read up on
anything that interests
you or you can do
research on anything.
So you can read up on
dinosaurs, for example.
I've been reading up
on dinosaurs lately and
did you know that, you know, the
Brantosaurus is not a real dinosaur anymore?
That's right.
Okay.
So we've been reading
up on the advantages of
homeschooling and he
starts by, well, defending
his position on what
the advantages are with
the phrase, well, first of all, alright,
this is an important little phrase.
This is something you
can use like you say,
Marco, when you're
going to have an argument
or maybe a discussion
about something and you
want to tell your points,
your side of the argument.
And so first of all, means I have
a list, but this is my first point.
Right.
So it's a nice little
phrase to open up this
list of things that you're
going to say, right?
That's right.
So you should drink orange juice, Marco,
because first of all, it tastes good.
Second of all, but also it's
very good for your body.
So first of all, it's the first main point.
So you can say second
of all, can you go like
third of all, fourth of
all, not really, right?
No, you don't really
say it, I guess you
could, but so you go
first of all, second of
all, and then maybe just go and
also or lastly and then lastly to end it.
Okay.
Very good.
Now one of the other
points that he talked
about, well, apart from
the one on one class
was that the reason why
a one on one class was
better is because he could focus on
his or her strengths and or weaknesses.
All right.
So strengths or weaknesses or strengths
and weaknesses, this is a set phrase.
And it's important to remember
that these two words are opposites.
So strengths, that's the
things you're good at.
Right.
And weaknesses.
Things you're bad at.
Especially when you're
studying in a school
or you're homeschooling,
it's important that
the teacher understands the
strengths and weaknesses of the student.
Right.
Because something
that you're really good
at, maybe you should
encourage and something
you're bad at, you should
work harder at improving.
That's right.
So it's usually fixed phrase.
You'll even get it in job
interviews, somebody
will say, well, what do you think
are your strengths and weaknesses?
That's right.
So remember that phrase,
strengths and weaknesses.
Okay.
And lastly, he said
that, well, even though
the idea is interesting,
it might be difficult
to make the parents or the
grandparents agree with him.
So he said he will bring
it up over Sunday brunch.
Okay.
I will bring it up.
Mmm.
Bring it up.
Well, you're not actually
holding something.
This means that you will
mention it in conversation.
Mention the topic.
Right.
That's right.
Your grandma and
grandpa don't think
homeschooling is a good
idea, but you will discuss
it or you will suggest it
during Sunday brunch.
Right.
So if you want to discuss
a topic, you usually
say, I will bring it up with
the president for example.
That's right.
You will talk about it
with the with the president.
You can also say, please don't bring it up.
Right.
So maybe you told a secret and you
don't want the other person to know.
You say, oh, okay, please
Marco, don't bring it up.
Okay.
Very good.
Listen to her dialogue one last time.
I think we should homeschool our
children when we decide to have kids.
What?
Why?
Well, our public
schools here are not very
good and prime schools
are just too expensive.
I have been reading up on some homeschooling
and it has a lot of advantages.
Like what?
I think that by doing
something like that, we would
be isolating our children
from social interaction.
Well, first of all, I
would be able to teach
them everything they learned in
school in a more relaxed and fun way.
I also think that having
a one-on-one class
is much better since you can focus
more on his or her strengths or weaknesses.
I think neither your parents or
mine would agree to such an idea.
I'll bring it up over Sunday brunch.
Good luck with that.
Okay.
So homeschooling is a
very interesting option.
I think it's very common, more common
nowadays in Britain and North America.
But how do people that
are homeschooled go to
college if they didn't
go to a high school?
Well, I believe that most people when they
finish homeschooling will take some tests
to prove that they've actually learned
the material that is required by the state.
Because in America, each state
sets the educational standards.
And so it's important that you
learn certain science and math skills.
And then once you take those tests, you
would get your GED, your graduate diploma.
That means that you've learned everything
that a high school student should know.
Right.
So it's interesting because
it would seem a little
bit strange to not want
your kid to go to school.
But at the same time,
there are many reasons
why parents don't want their kids
to go to school like in this dialogue.
Maybe the schools are not
really good or too expensive.
What do you think about homeschooling?
Would you send your kids to homeschool?
I don't think I would do
homeschooling because
I think it's really
important for students
to or for children to
learn how to get along
with others and to
learn to negotiate and
to learn to play and
to also learn to respect
their teachers because
you have a different
relationship with your parents
than you do your teachers.
Right.
I think there's a lot of valuable
social lessons you can learn at school.
But I do understand why
a lot of people choose
this option, especially
if the schools in
their area are poor performing schools so
that the students aren't learning enough.
Or if maybe they're not safe because there's
some bullying or there's some violence
and so for those reasons I definitely
understand the motivation to do homeschooling.
But then again, you can't, I
mean you can get homeschooled
from kindergarten all the
way to high school, right?
But there is no
homeschooling for university
unless you do like an online
degree or something like that.
You can't really be
homeschooling for college.
No, there's distance
courses so you could
use the internet and learn online but
now you can't homeschool for university.
It's a very debatable
topic, a lot of people
defend it saying it's
good, it brings parents
closer together to
their kids, that kids
enjoy learning, that
they learn better, etc.
Other people don't
really agree with it so what
is your opinion do you
agree with homeschooling?
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to hear your arguments there.
Okay, we'll see you there.
Bye.